# MARIA MANUEL

(415) 916-9449

Sacramento & San Francisco CA

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am an avid learner whose passion is driven by problem-solving. My interest in technology began 15 years ago as a legal assistant while training new hires on desktop applications. I am further developing my tech skills in systems support and web development. I am currently seeking an internship or junior-level position. Let's connect. I look forward to meeting you soon.

### **SKILLS**

OS: Windows, macOSDatabase: NoSQL, Access

• Software: MS Office, G Suite

CMS: WordPress

• Coding: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

· Coding: Python, Jinja, Linux

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

#### M.E.D.A

 Front-end web development -November 2023

#### **Kickstart Coding**

 Back-end web development expected September 2024

#### CompTia

 A+ certification - expected June 2024

#### **EDUCATION**

City College of San Francisco Expected in 12/2024

**Associate of Science:** Information Technology

City College of San Francisco 06/2020

Associate of Science: Health Education

#### LINKS

- https://maria-manuel.com
- https://github.com/maria-manuel
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/maria-m-443143255/

### **WORK HISTORY**

San Francisco Living Wage Coalition - Intern - Web Developer San Francisco, CA • 10/2022 - Current

- Collaborate effectively and communicate professionally with members of the development team.
- Shadow senior team members to learn new tasks.
- Problem-solve to determine appropriate debug/testing processes.
- Improve website functionality by updating plugins and extensions.
- · Troubleshoot and conduct standup of resolved technicalities.
- Craft strategy and intuitive interface to achieve prominent organizational purpose for internal and external clients.
- Coordinate with manager to obtain content for updates/expansions.
- Make recommendations for new features based on suitability and alignment with business goals.
- Maintained websites of 3 campaigns using best practices to serve diverse groups across all genres according to client's needs.
- Perform duties using attention to detail in design and web content using HTML and CMS
- Manage 3 sites via WordPress content management system.

Volunteer Service - Caregiver

San Francisco, CA • 02/2015 - 07/2022

- Supervised and built strong relationship with seriously ill patient.
- · Organized and supported activities of daily living.
- Documented sleep and eating patterns in medical record books.

McClellan & Corren - Legal Assistant

South San Francisco, CA • 10/2013 - 01/2015

 Act independently while supporting and monitoring database by proactively administering case development.

- Administered data by effectively utilizing best practices.
- Provided end-user support addressing desktop application issues.
- Assisted in management of projected workflow for rotating assistants.
- Surpassed firm objectives by cooperating with staff to implement project management initiatives and met projected deadlines by at least 1 day, ahead of schedule.
- Performed research and conferred with parties of all levels to gather, document and review information.
- Communicated effectively verbally and in writing as appropriate under the direction of attorneys.

## Lewis, Brisbois, Bisgaard & Smith - Legal Assistant San Francisco, CA • 11/2011 - 06/2013

- Assist non-technical staff and attorneys with support addressing desktop application issues. Served as technical liaison.
- Modified database to accurately reflect case status documentation.
- Assisted department in added responsibilities in order to meet team goals with a positive attitude.
- Handled multiple projects simultaneously for 3 attorneys.
- Responded to all clients in a professional and courteous manner.
- Proofread/edited a high volume of medical-legal records.

# Law Offices Of Mullen & Filippi - Legal Secretary San Francisco, CA • 10/2006 - 10/2011

- Use initiative as the resident expert of desktop applications by utilizing all available resources.
- · Manage and maintain pertinent legal information in database.
- Monitored cases while observing confidentiality with extreme discretion and delegated tasks, under the direction of attorneys.
- Proofread/edited court correspondence and medical summaries.
- Conferred with medical professionals of all levels including courthouses for research and gathered information.